SALIM MSALLAM RASHID

salim.rashid65@gmail.com | 0719 714 921 Date of Birth:21-OCT-1991. PASSPORT NUMBER: AK0437919. DRIVING LICENSE NUMBER: YWB094.

OPERATIONS, PROCUREMENT & SUPPLY CHAIN MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL

Accomplished and process-oriented professional with history of strengthening compliance; improving processes; and elevating output, quality, customer satisfaction and employee morale to all-time best. Excel at coordinating tasks of numerous internal divisions and external agencies to ensure rapid, accurate delivery of equipment, materials, and resources. Track record of identifying redundancies and maximizing resources to streamline operations. Relied on to drive top-line and bottom-line gains regardless of supply chain challenges and industry obstacles. Proven time management skills, high attention to detail and experienced in managing numerous tasks simultaneously. Renowned as a motivational and inspirational team leader capable of training and developing teams to enable them to fulfil their potential and add value to the business.

KEY STRENGTHS

- ✓ Operations Management
- ✓ Strategic Planning
- ✓ Procurement
- ✓ Policies & Procedures Compliance
- ✓ Relationship Building
- ✓ Forecasting/Budgeting
- ✓ Administrative Functions
- ✓ Project Management
- ✓ Supply Chain Management
- ✓ Quality Assurance
- ✓ Continuous Improvement
- ✓ Vendor & Staff Relations
- ✓ Team Supervision & Training
- ✓ Client Engagement

- ✓ Communication
- ✓ Negotiation/Persuasion
- ✓ Conflict/Problem Solving
- ✓ Time Management
- ✓ Organizational Skills
- √ Flexibility/Adaptability
- ✓ Leadership/Management

CAREER HISTORY

ALMARAI COMPANY • Dec 2021 to Present

LOGISTICS - MID-HAUL DELIVERY DRIVER

Responsibilities

- Ensures that the products are delivered and received by customers as scheduled and in full per invoice/ order.
- Timely delivery of all orders / products to customer location as per sequence and invoice.
- Operating delivery device to receive stocks from depot to customer.
- Unloads products from the vehicle to customer's place.
- Maintain the van cold chain as per SOP.
- Collects wastage / Buyback from GHC (Green House Champion) and reconciliation.
- · Collects enclosed invoices from GHC.
- Adheres to company HSS and quality policy to avoid any incidence to self and others.
- Ensures that the vehicle and its components are operating safely, efficiently and the products are handled safely.

NEOPLAN DESIGN-TECH • Jan 2018 to NOV 2021

PROJECT PROCUREMENT OFFICER

Responsibilities

- Effectively plan and schedule work at the site while overseeing the installation of temporary offices for site staff.
- Study the drawings and manage the labor, material, and machinery as per daily plan schedule
- Closely oversee the delivery of materials, tracks progress, and conducts safety checks while sorting out emerging problems that could hold up work as they arise.
- Controls operations and ensures work is done safely, on time and within budget and to the right quality standards.
- Constantly engage with clients and provides current work in progress updates to the site engineer and project financier(s).
- Utilizes tact, professionalism and diplomacy while resolving emerging conflicts during the entire project lifecycle.
- Establishes and maintains a continuous and working relationship with company suppliers.

Key Achievements

- · Successfully planned and supervised three housing projects from their beginning up to their completion.
- Improved and developed skills in project management; financial management; negotiations and procurement; communication and working as part of a team.

COMPASS GROUP PLC • Aug 2017 to Mar 2017

WAREHOUSE ASSISTANT

Responsibilities

Effectively conducted the processes of acceptance, delivery, build-up, and breakdown of cargo consignments and operated
equipment as required for movement of loads.

- Oversaw the loading/unloading cargo from the ULDs/aircraft/trucks as directed.
- Directed and assisted the team of porters and equipment operators in cargo handling, in accordance with the standard principles, while complying with published QAS performance standards.
- Inspected, validated against relevant documents, and counted goods at every point of delivery, acceptance, breakdown and built-up while ensuring that goods conformed to relevant criteria, and were stored and dispatched in accordance with standard work procedures and requirements.
- Ensured a high degree of customer service, attentiveness, speed, and control error rates whilst maintaining consistency in service standards.
- Ensured that handling of special cargo fully complies with the current edition of IATA manuals and are loaded in accordance with the same.
- Enforced safety and security procedures while handling cargo.

Key Achievements

- Got exposed to working with a culturally diversified team at international level.
- · Gained extensive knowledge of the aviation industry operations particularly in cargo handling operations.
- Excelled within very busy schedules and deadlines while maintaining speed and accuracy.
- Trained on ensuring and maintaining safety within workplace environment.

FOREMOST (K) LIMITED • Oct 2016 to Feb 2017

PROCUREMENT OFFICER

Responsibilities

- Provided overall guidance, mentoring, and supervision to procurement, finance, and logistics employees on matters procurement.
- Prepared and maintained purchasing records, price lists, and management reports including customs clearance documentation.
- Conducted continuous research through comparative analysis to ascertain the best products and suppliers in terms of best value, delivery speed, and quality.
- · Utilized strong persuasion skills to negotiate and manage contractual agreements with local and international suppliers.
- Developed and maintained constructive and cooperative working business relationships with suppliers including carrying out of supply contracts risk assessments.

Key Achievements

- Introduced digital means of capturing data at the company's main storage facility.
- Successfully coordinated all procurement activities and provided leadership to a new school project (Foremost Integrated Academy, Nyali) that was built in Nyali, Mombasa-Kenya.
- Developed strong negotiating skills by participating in negotiations with company suppliers.

EAST AFRICA PORTLAND CEMENT COMPANY LIMITED ● Sep 2014 to Oct 2014

STORES MANAGEMENT TRAINEE

Responsibilities

- · Received and verified stock against delivery notes.
- · Issued stock against authorized purchase requisitions.
- Conducted periodic inventory audits.
- Reconciled issuance of stock and giving out reports.
- Ensuring that the store was properly arranged according to set procedures.

Key Achievements

- Learnt how to enter data into an Enterprise Resource Planner-Oracle JDE
- Gained knowledge on inventory management processes that involved stock receiving, issuing, invoicing, account reconciliation, and report generation.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION

Masters of Arts(Project planning and Management)-University of Nairobi (ongoing)
Monitoring and Evaluation Certificate- Amref International University (Year 2021)
CIPS Diploma- Chartered Institute of Procurement and Supply (Year 2015)
Bachelor of Commerce, Procurement & Supply chain management Option (Year 2014)

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Member- Chartered Institute of Procurement and Supply (005539667)

Member - Kenya Institute of Supply Management (69888)

National construction authority-Construction site supervisor (NCA/SS/2018/30411)

REFEREES

Eric OndaraAssistant Site Engineer,
Kenya Rural Roads Authority

Kennedy MuthokaFinance Officer, East Africa Portland
Cement

Kassam DadaDirector, Foremost Limited
T: +254 722662190

T: +254700727379 E:ericondara@gmail.com

T: +254716356724

E: kennedymuthoka34@yahoo.com

E: kassam@foremostlimited.co.ke